Sandra Williams, PHR, Human Resources Manager, HRBP

Houston, TX - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/64dd8b0ce8ae407d

HR professional with 15 years experience partnering with hiring managers to strategize and support their human resources and human capital needs. Responsible for the execution of all human resource processes and programs to ensure quality results that positively impact business.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Human Resources Manager

IpDatatel, LLC - October 2013 to Present

IpDatatel, LLC engineers cutting edge internet devices for home automation. IpDatatel was recognized as No. 8 in the Houston Business Journals 100 fastest growing companies in 2013 and recently was recognized as No. 4 in 2014.

Entered a company undergoing rapid expansion as the first ever HR Manager. With no established HR presence or practices, built the HR department from the ground up to implement HR policy standards, procedures and compliance.

- * Strategic HR business partner responsible for developing and implementing all policies and procedures that support the organizations goals and objectives.
- * Implemented and standardized workforce planning processes, onboarding, off-boarding, performance management, and succession management
- * Partnered with the executive team to create and drive a shared vision of values and ethics for the organization
- * Mentor, coach and advise hiring managers regarding employee relations issues
- * Provided training regarding progressive discipline procedures, interviewing, and employee relations
- * Implementing performance management system
- * Extremely effective working with different business units and building relationships with managers, clients and vendors
- * Recruiting business partner providing recruiting support to different divisions and assisting managers and advising in regards to hiring needs

AIG - Talent Acquisition Consultant

AIG - Houston, TX - July 2012 to October 2013

Position was relocated to California)

Talent Consultant providing support regarding human capital needs within AIG.

HR Consultant

- March 2008 to July 2012

Responsibilities

Providing HR consulting support within the business units of clients such as Partners Consulting, Sungard Consulting, IHS Corporation, and Dyonyx Corporation, respectively.

* Serve as a HR business partner within the different business units to partner with management teams to strategize and understand hiring needs.

- *Attend management and task force meetings to discuss staffing needs, staffing forecasting, employee/client issues, etc.
- *Experienced working within professional services organizations
- *Established and implemented New Hire Orientation and the on boarding process and procedures of new hires.
- *Work closely with management and provide coaching and counseling of HR hiring processes.
- *Reviewed prospects for benefit renewal plans.
- *Assist with effort regarding Affirmative Action requirements for Government Contract projects
- *Provide full lifecycle recruitment for all positions across the board. Entry level up to director level.
- *Identify Universities, Trade Schools, networking groups to identify and recruit new candidate pool.
- *Coordinate and attend Job Fairs, University Campus recruiting, networking functions, etc.
- *Work with management to prepare effective job descriptions.
- *Source, interview and recruit candidates nationwide.
- *Monitor and track candidate information into ATS (including Taleo) in order to maintain candidate/applicant database.
- *Utilized all methods of recruiting to identify viable candidates including job boards, job postings, search engines, Social Media(Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, BullHorn Reach, etc...), cold calling etc. with knowledge of Boolean search strings
- *Facilitate interviews and debrief meetings with management regarding candidate interviews.
- *Experienced working with third party vendors for staffing needs.
- *Partner with management to communicate Human Resources policies, procedures, programs and laws.
- *Assist with employee relations, benefits, salary issues.
- *Assist with additional Human Resources duties as needed.

Recruiter

Staffing Agency - Houston, TX - June 2006 to March 2008

Responsibilities

STAFFING INDUSTRY 06/99-05/99, 07/06 -03/08 Houston, Texas

Administaff

GDH Consulting

Steverson

DirectFit (Formerly Integrated Partnership)

Agency recruiting experienced with all aspects of the recruiting process including direct sourcing of candidates and managing candidate flow through the entire interview process. Industries include but are not limited to: Financial, Information Technology, Oil and Gas, Energy Trading, Manufacturing, Healthcare, and Professional Services.

- *Provided recruiting services for various clients nationwide.
- *Responsible for full life cycle recruiting process of all open job positions.
- *Worked closely and consulted with all levels of management to build relationships and help understand client needs and corporate culture to ensure a good candidate fit.
- *Day to day interaction with clients to manage interview process to placement.
- *Engage in client candidate interviews to assess candidate skills vs. client's job requirement.
- *Work closely with candidates to cultivate relationships and assist in growing local database.
- *Methods of recruiting included but not limited to cold calling, Internet sourcing, networking, and employee referrals
- *Client industries include but are not limited to: Financial, Oil and Gas, Manufacturing and Healthcare
- *Positions include IT technical, non-technical positions, entry-level up to management level positions.

Resource Manager

Executive Direction, Inc - Houston, TX - May 2004 to July 2006

Perform HR Generalist duties

- * Assist with the on boarding process of new hires.
- * Partner with management to communicate Human Resources policies, procedures, programs and laws.
- * Assist with employee relations, benefits, salary issues.
- * Point of contact for managers regarding hiring needs, training and development, performance issues and compensation issues
- * Strategized with hiring managers to understand talent needs.
- * Assisted with on boarding process of new hires/new hire orientation.
- * Work with contracts department providing necessary information for new hires/visa requirements
- * Responsible for entire recruiting process for the Minneapolis market for all open positions.
- * Recruited for contract and permanent positions.
- * Positions included but were not limited to Project Managers, Business Analyst, and Java/J2EE/.NET Developers.
- * Identified candidates via external web based methods, referrals, and independent sourcing techniques.
- * Analyzed job requirements to qualify candidates for good candidate fit.
- * Worked with managers regarding performance management.
- * Counseled and coached employees regarding performance issues/client issues or any issues not compliant with company policies and procedures.
- * Daily compliance of employment laws

HR Resource Manager

Alternative Resource Corporation - Houston, TX - October 1997 to April 1999

Provided HR support to 80 employees on client projects

- * Performed human resources generalist duties
- * Assist with the on boarding process of new hires.
- * Partnered with management to communicate Human Resources policies, procedures, programs and laws.
- * Assist with employee relations, benefits, salary issues.
- * Provided new hire orientation
- * Assisted employees and contractors with benefit enrollment
- * Answered all questions and assisted with issues regarding company benefits
- * Worked closely with management to discuss performance reviews
- * Administered and maintained performance and salary reviews
- * Counseled employees regarding performance issues/client issues or any issues not compliant with company policies and procedures
- * Advised employees on career development
- * Coordinated involvement in Career Fair recruitment

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Business Administration

University of Houston - Houston, TX